<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://npanczyk.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://npanczyk.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2023-11-07T18:49:09+00:00</updated><id>https://npanczyk.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>My professional portfolio. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Nuclear needs a makeover</title><link href="https://npanczyk.github.io/blog/2023/nuclear-makeover/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nuclear needs a makeover"/><published>2023-11-07T11:40:16+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-07T11:40:16+00:00</updated><id>https://npanczyk.github.io/blog/2023/nuclear-makeover</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://npanczyk.github.io/blog/2023/nuclear-makeover/"><![CDATA[<p>No one expects computer engineers to have to advocate for their line of work. The same goes for mechanical, civil, electrical, materials– the list goes on. Society generally sees value in making faster computer chips, automating laborious processes, and designing structurally sound bridges. These are some (of many) applications to the aforementioned fields, and most demand for these industries is driven by consumers.</p> <p>Nuclear engineers, on the other hand, not only operate as the brains behind some of the most complicated physical systems known to man, they are also responsible for creating demand for their designs through <em>public outreach <em>. While, of course there will always be a demand for electrons, consumers would often prefer if these electrons came from wind, solar, hydropower, or maybe even natural gas. Few individuals would react positively to the notion of a nuclear power plant being the closest electricity generation technology to their home, yet this is exactly what the nuclear industry must advocate for. This advocacy comes in the form of a grassroots movement of scientists and energy experts working on a person-to-person basis of “debunking nuclear myths.” And therein lies the problem.</em></em></p> <p>“Debunking” implies the existence of an incorrect preconception. This is the uphill battle the nuclear industry must face today as a result of decades of bad press through the atrocities of the nuclear weapons program and global nuclear accidents.</p> <p>To clarify, the nuclear advocacy in question strictly regards nuclear energy generation, not nuclear weapons. <em>Ironically and ethically questionable as it may be, there’s already plenty of demand for that line of work…<em></em></em></p> <p>Because we know the nuclear industry is working against the perceptions of general society, we need to reframe how people think about nuclear, not just inform them about it. Think about it like boiling ice water versus tepid water– both can be boiled, but one requires significantly more energy to get there. This energy must come in the form of rebranding: nuclear needs a makeover.</p> <p>Professor Steve Cohen from the Columbia Climate School <a href="https://news.climate.columbia.edu/2022/05/31/environmental-sustainability-as-a-business-opportunity-and-risk/">writes</a>, “…in the long run, products that pollute will be more expensive than those that do not.” This is the kind of investment that the public must recognize they are making with nuclear– an investment into the clean energy future. Fast Company recently asked Jones Knowles Ritchie, an independent creative agency, to come up with a new look for nuclear. The <a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/90951504/jones-knowles-ritchie-rebrands-nuclear-power">branding</a> featured “forward-focused” images, like electric vehicles and spacecraft to help establish nuclear energy as a source of the future, not just of the past. It also employed a double “o” to represent the splitting of atoms during nuclear fission, a nod to the physics of the industry.</p> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/img/nuc_brand-480.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/img/nuc_brand-800.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/img/nuc_brand-1400.webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/nuc_brand.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> <p><em> Image courtesy of Jones Knowles Ritchie via www.fastcompany.com.<em></em></em></p> <p>Unfortunately, rebranding nuclear energy is going to take a lot more than one clever billboard. Still, one of the most challenging parts of implementing nuclear, and therefore the largest barrier to reaping the benefits of its plentiful, carbon-free electrons, is getting the public on board. <a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/astro_teller_the_unexpected_benefit_of_celebrating_failure/transcript">Astro Teller remarks</a> on TED, “The only way to get people to work on big, risky things – audacious ideas – and have them run at all the hardest parts of the problem first, is if you make that the path of least resistance for them.” Before we can truly start implementing new nuclear technologies and powering our future with clean energy, we must overcome our biggest hurdle of public perception. That doesn’t mean laying low and letting nuclear fly under the radar; this would yield a path of resistance. It also doesn’t mean spewing technical information about reactors into people’s ears (tempting as it may be, this is almost never effective). Instead, making a path of least resistance means getting in front of the public with nuclear’s big, bold, fresh, new look and letting individuals decide on their own terms. It’s time to take the bull by the horns– nuclear’s future depends on it.</p> <h4 id="sources">Sources</h4> <ul> <li>Cohen, Steve. “Environmental Sustainability as a Business Opportunity and Risk.” State of the Planet, Columbia Climate School, May 2022.</li> <li>Salazar, David. “Nuclear power could be the cornerstone of a clean-energy future—but it needs better branding.” Fast Company, October 2023.</li> <li>Teller, Astro. “The unexpected benefit of celebrating failure.” TED, February 2016.</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="nuclear-outreach"/><category term="nuclear,"/><category term="outreach,"/><category term="branding"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[why we must rebrand a stigmatized industry]]></summary></entry></feed>